If you want to start Amazon KDP, but you
don't know where to start, well, you're
in the right place. Because if I had to
start over from zero again, this is
exactly how I would do it. In this
video, I'm going to give you a complete
Amazon KDP tutorial for beginners. So,
if you're overwhelmed by conflicting
advice, or you want a clear step-by-step
roadmap, this video is for you. You
don't need prior experience, you don't
need an existing audience. Amazon KDP is
an extremely beginner-friendly business
model. So, let's get right into it. Once
again, this is going to be a complete
Amazon KDP tutorial for beginners. And
my goal in this video is to give you
roadmap to get to your first $1,000 per
month. Because in Amazon KDP, we always
say that if you can do $1,000, you can
do $10,000. If you can do $10,000, you
can do $100,000. Because all you have to
do is rinse and repeat a few simple
steps over and over and over until
you're happy with how much you're
making. Now, with that being said, a
very quick disclaimer is that I
obviously cannot guarantee any results.
Because this is a real business, and a
real business takes time, effort,
energy, and I cannot control how much
you're going to put into this, and
that's why I cannot guarantee any
results. All I can say is that I've made
a lot of money in this business model. I
have a lot of students crushing it as
well. So, I know it works if you
actually try and take action, but that
is all up to you. So, first, let's start
with who is Sean? Who am I? Because it's
important to listen to someone who has
the results that you're trying to get.
So, I started publishing in 2016, so
it's been 10 years since I've been doing
this. I hit $10,000 per month in 10
months of starting this, and I went on
and built a multiple six-figures-a-year
KDP business. I was generating multiple
six-figures-a-year, and I ran that for
multiple years. And a few years later, I
sold that first KDP account for
$820,000,
which made me a self-made millionaire at
age 26 doing this business, right? Not
teaching, not selling courses, actually
doing this business. And right after I
sold it, I started a new Amazon KDP
account, which also hit six figures a
year. And since then, I've been
maintaining that six figures a year run
rate for multiple years. So, at this
point, I focus more on teaching, right?
Through my YouTube videos. I do have a
course coaching program that I sell, but
typically when people transition to
selling courses, they neglect the
business that they have. But I'm over
here still making six figures a year
from my own KDP business. I'm still
doing this 10 years in. And if you don't
believe anything I say, I documented my
entire journey of building this business
in this KDP income report playlist,
which you can just look it up on my
channel, and all the videos there. So, I
was able to quit my 9-5 job and travel
the world, all thanks to Amazon KDP. So,
I lived in many different countries,
many different locations. This is in
Bali, Indonesia. This is in Thailand.
This is in China. This is in Hawaii.
I've also lived a bit in Europe and
Latin America. And that's the beauty of
this business model is that everything
is online. All you need is a laptop and
an internet connection. So, that's
exactly why I can move around like this,
live in different countries, and still
make money online. So, Amazon KDP
absolutely changed my life. I was broke.
I was working a 9-5 trying to make
something happen. This was the first
business that I was ever successful in.
And that is the case for a lot of
people. This is the first business model
that they actually make money with. And
that is because, again, this business
model is way simpler than others, and
it's extremely beginner-friendly. And
for that reason why we have thousands of
students inside our programs that are
actually making money with this. We got
students doing $7,000 a month, $5,000,
$6,000, €3,000 a month, and much, much
more. In fact, I brought on some of our
students and interviewed them on this
channel, and I compiled all those
interviews on a playlist called student
results and success stories, which I
highly encourage you to go and watch. We
got students doing literally $200,000
profit per month, $23,000 per month,
$4,000 profit. We got a single mom
working four jobs that's doing over
$10,000 per month. So, once again,
hopefully that shows you that this is
possible. You just have to understand
that this is a real business, and what
you get out of it depends on what you
put into it. So, let's get started with
the actual meat of this video. So, what
is Amazon KDP? Well, Amazon KDP is
Amazon's self-publishing platform. It's
completely free. There's no monthly fee,
no sign-up fee, nothing. So, everyone
can sign up and start publishing their
books on this. Now, the reason why
Amazon KDP, in my opinion, is the best
business model to get started,
especially if you're a beginner, or if
you just want freedom, okay? And that is
because you don't have to deal with any
inventory, since this is a
print-on-demand model, which means
Amazon only prints your books out once
you make a sale and ships it to the
customer. Or, if you sell ebooks or
audiobooks, it's all digital. So, you
have absolutely no inventory, you don't
have to deal with that. You don't have
to do any customer service, because
Amazon does all of that for you. You got
high profit margins with the digital
product. It's open to almost everyone in
the whole world, right? We're talking
Amazon. Amazon is the biggest online
retail store in the whole world. And
they're not going anywhere, okay?
Amazon's just going to keep expanding
and take over the world eventually. So,
it's also good for us to be nice to
Amazon right now when that happens. The
learning curve is very low, and the
reason why the learning curve is low is
because you don't have to learn a lot of
the things that you normally have to
learn in other business models. In other
business models, you're the one that's
doing the inventory, the customer
service, shipping and handling, right?
And because you have to do those,
obviously you have to learn how those
things work. But because Amazon handles
all of this for you, you don't have to
learn it, which means it's a lot easier
to get started. And because everything
is digital, you don't have to deal with
the fees of manufacturing the product,
shipping and handling, inventory, the
startup cost is very low as well. And
the main thing compared to other
business models is low competition. Now,
competition still exists, because
there's not a single business model that
has no competition, but compared to
other business models, it's less
competition. As an example, the yellow
circles here represents how many
physical products are being sold on
Amazon. So, if you're doing Amazon FBA
selling physical products, you're
competing with all these circles, right?
But compared to that, the red circles
here in the corner represents how many
books are sold on Kindle, which is, as
you can see, a lot less. So, the mindset
you want to have as you build this
business this is, once again, not a
get-rich-quick scheme. It's slow in the
beginning to build up, but as you build
it, things keep snowballing bigger and
bigger and bigger, and the momentum
really keeps going. And also, once you
build your income, it sustains pretty
well as well. So, you're building
passive income that will last for years.
That's what you should be reminding
yourself of. Because with all the other
business models, if you stop building
the business, your income usually dies
immediately. But with this business
model, once your book is out there, it's
out there, right? You don't have to do
anything, it's still going to be on
Amazon. It could continue to sell for
months, if not years. We have a lot of
students who, for whatever reason, leave
the business model, stop working on it,
and for years, they keep getting paid
month after month. So, yes, you can make
money short-term, but you also want to
kind of see this as a long-term
investment. And we're learning a
valuable skill that we can apply in, you
know, other businesses that we might
build in the future. So, these are the
types of books you can publish.
Essentially, you can categorize the type
of books in three different categories.
First is the high-content books, and
we're talking traditional non-fiction,
fiction books. These are the books that
you probably think of when you first
hear books. Next is medium-content
books. So, we're talking puzzle books,
coloring books, activity books, a lot of
pretty design-heavy books in this
category. And the last one is
low-content books, like journals,
planners, barely no content inside, and
that's why we call it low-content books.
And in terms of how you want to look at
it, this is a little graphic that I
created, but essentially, you have the
low content in the bottom, and you see
that this is the biggest in the pyramid,
right? So, what the size is representing
is competition. Low content is
significantly easier to create compared
to medium or high content, because it's
literally low in content, so it's very
easy to whip it up. But because these
books are easy to create, most people
are doing this. And because most people
are doing it, obviously you will be
competing with most people. And for that
reason, you typically make the least
amount of money. Now, if you move up to
medium content here, you have a little
less competition, because these books
are a little harder to create. And
because when something is hard, not a
lot of people want to do it, everybody
gravitates towards the easy way out,
right? So, if you can be the one that
does something a little bit harder, now
you cut down the competition, and
typically you make more money. Now, if
you go all the way up to high content,
this is the hardest book to create,
because it has a lot of content inside.
It takes a little bit more time, and for
that reason, the least amount of people
are trying to do this, which means you
have the least amount of competition,
and typically these books makes you the
most amount of money. Now, with that
being said, though, what's happening
nowadays that's crazy is that AI is
making high-content book creation very
easy. So, despite the competition being
the smallest, it's actually not that
hard to create, which I'm going to show
you in this video later on. So, I would
say the opportunity right now with
high-content books is better than ever.
But if you're thinking, "What if I'm not
an expert, right? How do I create these
books without being an expert?" Well,
you have to understand that the value
comes from organizing the information
and teaching it in an easy-to-understand
way, not from having new information. If
you read books pretty often, if you
consume content in any medium, most of
the time, the information is not new,
right? You probably heard of that
information before. But a lot of times,
people just want reminders. So, just
reminding them of the same thing is
enough, but at the same time, organizing
this information in an
easy-to-understand way in form of a book
is also a value. You save people a lot
of time. So, the value doesn't have to
be new information. It can be just
saving time. And for that value of
saving time, people are willing to pay,
you know, up to $20 for a book, right?
So, that's how you want to look at it.
But also, you can learn as you go,
right? As you publish these books,
you're obviously going to be learning
about the topic. So, you can eventually
become an expert, but you don't have to
start off that way. So, as we produce
these books, very important to keep in
mind that quality over everything, okay?
We're producing high-quality books that
people love. That is how you win in this
business. We are not spamming
low-quality books and tricking people
into buying low-quality books. Like,
that's not what we're doing here. And we
also can utilize AI. This is optional,
but I highly recommend it, right? You
can create better books faster with AI.
That's the whole purpose of AI. It's not
to just spam garbage, right? It's to
help us do things better at a faster
rate. So, with that being said, we move
on to actual step-by-step how-to here.
So, step one, we want to start with
keyword research. So, first, we want to
download this Chrome plugin called DS
Amazon Quick View. It's completely free.
I'll leave a link to this in the
description. Now, it's completely
optional, but you can also choose to
invest in Book Beam. This is the best
paid keyword research software out
there. But again, this is a paid
subscription. Now, you want to write
down any topic that comes into your
mind. So, whatever passion, interest,
hobbies, any ideas that are flowing into
your brain right now, just start writing
it down into a pen and paper. To get
more ideas, you can search the Amazon
best-selling categories, and just start
seeing what kind of books are selling,
and you can get more ideas there. So,
this is how you go to the best-sellers
category. Literally, just click on
best-sellers right here, go to books,
and from there you can go into different
categories. Like, I can do crafts,
hobbies, and home here, and I'm seeing a
lot of coloring books ranking in this
category. So, what you see here is from
DS Amazon Quick View, which is this
plugin right here. So, just look this up
on the Chrome Store. Once again, it's
completely free. I also try and leave a
link in the description. And what you're
seeing here is from BookBeam, the paid
tool. The difference is that BookBeam
calculates how much the book is making
based on the sales rank that you see
here. So, this one book is doing $2,000
per day. This book is doing $1,600 per
day in royalties. Pretty crazy, right?
Now, what you're seeing here, this is
called the best-sellers rank, and this
is Amazon telling us how well the book
is selling. In terms of this number, the
lower the better. So, if it's number one
in books, then that means it's the
number one best-selling book in the
entire bookstore. So, this is 48 in
books, meaning it's the 48th
best-selling book in the entire
bookstore. So, that's very, very good.
So, you can do a brain dump to get
ideas. You can also search different
Amazon categories and start getting
ideas. Like, these are all ideas, right?
Like, a book on United States coins, you
know, selling very well. We have adult
swear words coloring book doing really
well. Color by number mysteries, right?
So, a lot of book topics are popping up
right now. Another way you can get ideas
is using ChatGPT. So, I just asked,
"Give me 50 profitable book topics I can
write about for my Amazon KDP business."
And we have, you know, self-help like
dopamine detox, overthinking, emotional
intelligence, money, and career like
personal finance for beginners,
budgeting, and 50 more. Now, I
personally like this one, home and
lifestyle. We got decluttering for
overwhelmed adults. So, I do use
decluttering as an example often, so
let's take this. And essentially, after
you brain dump a bunch of different book
topics, you want to start searching that
on Amazon one by one. So, I took
decluttering, put it in the search bar,
and this is what we're seeing on page
one. So, this is how you validate if the
keyword is profitable or not. So, once
you search for the topic, you want to
look for other books with below 80,000
BSR. Because if a book is doing around
80,000 BSR, we can assume that it's
doing around $500 per month on average,
which is a pretty good benchmark to aim.
So, if you find three other books that
fits that criteria doing below 80,000
BSR, then we can safely assume that
that's a pattern, right? So, we can
assume that the keyword is profitable.
Now, if books on page one has low
reviews, that's also a good sign that
you don't need a ton of reviews to rank.
So, going back to the decluttering
keyword here, we have this book way
below 80,000 BSR, and for that reason
it's doing a lot more than $500 a month.
This is doing $252 per day. This is also
way below 80,000, doing a lot more than
that. This is 43,000, right? So, below
80,000. This one as well. So, we're
seeing multiple books below 80,000 BSR,
which tells us decluttering is a
profitable topic. Even this book right
here only has 26 reviews, and yet it's
below 80,000 BSR, making couple hundred
dollars a month. So, that is a good sign
if a book is selling with low reviews.
But, the main thing we're looking at is
the BSR number here. Once again, if you
don't have BookBeam, you can just look
at the same number using DS Amazon Quick
View. So, you want to repeat that
process for all the keywords that you
found, and once you find multiple
profitable keyword, you just choose the
one that you like the best, and then we
move on to step two. Step two is to
actually create the book. So, there are
many ways to create books. You can write
the book yourself if you want to and if
you have the ability to. You can also
hire a ghostwriter and outsource this
process, or you can use an AI software
like co-author.ai. The first step in the
book writing process is to create a book
outline. So, a book outline is
essentially a skeleton of the book. It's
very important to create this before you
actually write the book because if you
don't plan out the whole book, and you
just start randomly writing from, you
know, chapter one, you have no direction
and it's going to be very hard to write,
and the quality is probably not going to
be good. It's basically the equivalent
of me turning on the camera and I have
no script, no plan on what I'm going to
talk about, and I just start yapping in
my videos, right? So, obviously, we
don't want to do that. We want to create
an outline on, you know, the things that
we want to cover inside our book. So, to
create the book outline, we can look at
our top competitor table of contents and
their reviews, and we can get ideas on
what to include. We want to write down
chapters that stands out, and we want to
combine the best chapters from multiple
of our competitors and put it into our
book. So, essentially, learning from the
best-selling competitors, taking the
best parts of their book and put it into
ours. We also want to read the reviews
and write down what the customers liked
or didn't like about their books, and we
want to make sure to do the things that
people liked and avoid the things that
people didn't like. We also can use
ChatGPT to get more ideas. So, this is
how you do it. In my case, I'm doing
decluttering, so I'm just going to start
opening up my top competitors here, and
Amazon allows you to kind of stalk on
your competitors, right? So, you can
actually read sample here, and you can
scroll down to see their table of
contents. And from here, you start
reading it, right? And, you know, if you
feel like, "Oh, this chapter is really
cool. I really want to make sure my book
includes something like this as well."
then you put it into your outline. If
you feel like it's kind of fluff and you
don't think it's that important, then
you skip it. So, that's something you
can definitely do. You also can scroll
down to the review section and start
reading these positive and negative
reviews. And if you start seeing
patterns like people are always
complaining about the same thing, right?
People are saying, "Oh, I wish the
author covered this, but I'm
disappointed that it didn't cover this
thing." Well, you take note of that, and
you make sure that your book covers that
exact thing, right? If a lot of people
are loving something like, "Oh, I love
this part about the book." you take note
of that, and you make sure you do the
same thing as well. Now, a quick hack is
that you can literally copy this entire
thing, like highlight this entire thing,
and just paste it into ChatGPT, ask it
to summarize what people liked, what
people didn't like, and make this
process way, way faster. Or, you can ask
ChatGPT to create the entire book
outline. Now, quick disclaimer is that
ChatGPT is not perfect, right? This is a
very simple book outline. It works, but
it's not the best. But, this is how you
can kind of get started with it. So, I
just said to ChatGPT, "I'm creating a
book on decluttering. Please create a
detailed eight-chapter book outline."
And we have chapter one, why clutter is
draining your life. Chapter two, the
decluttering mindset that actually
works. Chapter three, your decluttering
game plan, and so on and so forth. Now,
what you can do is combine this with the
other strategies, right? Looking at, you
know, the competitor table of contents,
maybe changing few chapters from here to
what you got from ChatGPT, also looking
at the reviews, right? Make sure you add
the, you know, good things and the bad
things about your competitors inside
your book. And you want to make sure to
create a very detailed book outline, as
detailed as possible. And once that is
ready, it's time to actually start
filling out those chapters and start
writing the book. Now, a couple things
to understand here. In terms of the word
count and the trim size, if you're doing
high-content books like my decluttering
book is a high-content book, right? It's
a very typical non-fiction self-help
book. So, for these type of books, what
I recommend in terms of word count is
30,000 words. And for the trim size, I
recommend 5 by 8 to 6 by 9. Those two
sizes are the standard sizes in terms of
these type of books, and it depends on
the formatting, but this comes out to
around 150 to 200 pages, which is around
the perfect length. Anything shorter
than this, people will kind of complain
that it's too short, but anything longer
than this, and typically, you start kind
of having fluff in your book. And it's a
lot better to have a short and
straight-to-the-point book that's full
of good information compared to a
500-page book where 80% of the book is
just fluff and repeating the same thing
over and over and over, right? People
don't value more page count. What people
want is the highest value per time
invested, if that makes sense. In our
case, you can think of highest value per
page. So, if every single page has good
information, good storytelling, it's
packed with value, it is much, much
better than a way longer book where
people have to read through 10 pages
just to get one simple tip or something
like that. Now, that's for high-content.
Now, if you're doing low and
medium-content, your word count and trim
size depends. So, you just want to kind
of look at your competitors, see what
they're doing, and model them from
there. As an example, if you're trying
to create a coloring book, right? You
want to open up all your top
competitors, and you can see the
dimensions right here. This is a trim
size. So, if everyone else is doing 8.5
by 8.5 trim size, you probably want to
do the same thing. If everyone's doing
around 80 pages for their coloring book,
which is a typical length for the
coloring book, then you probably want to
do 80 pages or maybe a little bit more
to offer a little bit more value, right?
Even in the description, you will see
that, you know, they're offering 40
hand-drawn pages. If everyone's doing 40
hand-drawn pages, maybe try 45
hand-drawn pages, right? Offer a little
bit more value. So, always try and
compete with value. You know, be the
best book in the market. Next, we want
to create our book title. So, for
publishing non-fiction books, your book
title should have your main keyword, and
you want to add a little bit of flair to
it, right? So, in my case, my main
keyword is decluttering. If you have a
book on, let's say, ketogenic diet, your
main keyword is ketogenic diet. If you
have a book on how to stop overthinking,
your main keyword is how to stop
overthinking. You want to put that in
the title. The reason why is because
you're essentially telling Amazon what
your book is about. When you put
decluttering in the title, you're
telling Amazon that your book is about
decluttering. So, when people search for
decluttering on Amazon, your book has a
higher chance of showing up. If you skip
this and just create a fancy title, then
Amazon has no idea what your book is
about, and you have a way less chance of
showing up on page one. But, at the same
time, if I just say decluttering as a
title, that's boring, right? You still
want to sell the book, so that's why you
put keyword plus something else. Like,
in this case, as an example, I put
10-minute decluttering cheat sheet,
right? I put 10-minute before the
keyword and cheat sheet after. You know,
I could also do like decluttering made
simple. So, that's why you want to do
keyword plus spicing it up as the
formula. You want to refer to your
outline and add words that appeals to
your target audience. You want to get
inspiration from your competition, but
don't copy. You can use ChatGPT to get
more book title ideas, but make sure
it's unique enough from competitors.
That's another issue with ChatGPT is
that it often just kind of rehashes the
same thing over and over and over. So,
the output you get from it could be very
similar to what's already out on the
market, and that's why you want to make
sure that that's not the case, right?
You can get ideas from ChatGPT, but you
want to kind of edit it. So, I asked
ChatGPT to generate a book title for
this book adding the keyword
decluttering, and right off the bat, we
got decluttering made simple, right?
Funny because this is what I mentioned
earlier. Decluttering your life,
decluttering without the stress, and so
much more. So, should you use a pen name
or a real name? The honest answer is it
doesn't matter at all. Like, it's not
going to affect sales. So, if you're
shy, if you're not confident in putting
your name on a book and putting it out
there, you can definitely use a pen
name. It's completely fine. Like, J.K.
Rowling from the Harry Potter series is
a pen name, right? So, this is a very
common practice. But, at the same time,
what I will tell you is that if you have
any fear of putting your real name out
there, don't worry because no one's
going to judge you. Most of the time,
the fear that we feel is just our brain
making things up, and it's actually not
what's happening in real life. Again,
most likely no one's judging you. So,
you can be more confident and put your
name on a book if you want to. At the
same time, all my books are under a pen
name, so it's really up to you. And a
pen name could be a person or a brand
name. It does not matter. So, let's talk
about how to actually write the book. As
I said earlier, you have a couple
options here. You can do it yourself to
save money, or you can outsource to save
time. Now, this is up to you, but you
have to choose which one is best for
you. So, if you want to save money by
investing time, if you have like a
text-heavy book like decluttering, you
can just write the book yourself. If you
have design-heavy books like coloring
books, you can design the book yourself.
If you want to save time, but invest
money, then for text-heavy books, you
can outsource to a ghostwriter. For
design-heavy books, you can outsource to
designers and have them make the book.
As an example, there are a lot of
freelancers that will create entire low
and medium content books for you. So,
this person right here will create a
book cover and a book interior, so
basically an entire low-content book
like a journal for $75, and the quality
is pretty good. Now, if you want to
create coloring books, there's someone
that can help you with that, too. Like,
they can create these coloring pages for
just $10 a page. If you want to test out
these services, I'll leave a link in the
description below. And for text-heavy
books, you can outsource to
ghostwriters. Again, you can find plenty
of ghostwriters from many different
websites like Upwork and Fiverr, and you
can negotiate with them the rate and
start working with them. Now, if you do
choose to use a ghostwriter for
high-content books, the typical cost
that you're looking at is around 1 to
$2,000 per book, which is definitely not
cheap. And for that reason, nowadays I'm
shifting towards using AI and writing
the books myself. The best way to do
this is using coauthor.ai, which is a
software that I created by working with
a developer who sold a project to NASA.
So, he's the one that built out the
software. I'm the one that's guiding him
on exactly how to do this based on my 10
years of publishing experience and
knowing exactly how to structure a
best-selling book. So, coauthor makes
the entire book writing process super
simple. Everything is just step-by-step,
so you can follow along. It is a paid
tool, though, so you do have to pay a
little bit, but it's significantly
cheaper than using a ghostwriter. If you
want to check out coauthor, I'll leave a
link in the description, as well as I
filmed a separate video on the complete
step-by-step tutorial on how to use
coauthor.ai to write an entire book. So,
I'll also leave a link to the video in
the description. Now, if you're
wondering, "Why not just use ChatGPT or
Claude or Gemini?" Well, you definitely
can, but those are general AI tools, and
it's not specifically built just to
write high-quality books. So, typically
speaking, the quality of output you get
from those tools is worse than, you
know, a custom-designed AI software like
coauthor. But, depending on the book
topic, if you're creating a very, very
simple book that requires just simple
content, then you can definitely use
ChatGPT and other tools that you might
prefer. So, for a lot of books, it's not
good enough to produce a high-quality
book yet. But, for shorter list-type
books, those are pretty easy to make
with ChatGPT. As an example, this dad
jokes book is doing $100 a day in
royalties. And if you look inside, it's
just a compilation of one dad joke after
another. And to get something like this,
you can literally ask ChatGPT to write
me 10 dad jokes on animals, or 10 dad
jokes about sports, you know, really
anything. So, if you're using ChatGPT or
any AI tools, it's very important to
understand the do's and don'ts, what you
should and should not do. So, what you
should not do is to just copy-paste.
Okay, you never want to copy-paste from
AI because you want to use AI as a first
draft. From there, you should still add
your own content, your own stories, and
inputs to make the content your own.
It's very important to remember that AI
is not here to replace you in the book
creation process. AI is just here to
assist you, right? So, you're still
writing the book with AI. AI is not
writing the book for you. You also want
to fact-check a lot of the stuff because
AI is very confident in saying
something, but often times it's not
backed by anything. Like, it's just
random information, and it could be
wrong. So, if you would use ChatGPT to
start writing the actual content of the
book, you can ask something like this
where I just said, "Follow the outline
and write me the introduction chapter."
And since in the same conversation it
already generated the outline, it
started writing the introduction
chapter. Now, once again, if you use
normal AI softwares, typically what
happens is the introduction chapter is
completely fine. Chapter one is also
fine, but then around chapter two or
three, it becomes extremely repetitive,
and the information becomes more and
more surface level, which is a very
common problem using AI, and that's why
we created coauthor to overcome exactly
that issue. Once again, the problem with
using normal AI tools is that it's not
created for the sole purpose of
designing a best-selling book. It also
forgets what it wrote after a while, and
it becomes very, very repetitive. And
nine times out of 10, it's just
surface-level content and sometimes
incorrect information. So, yes, it's
possible to use ChatGPT or other generic
AI tools to write a book. You just have
to spend more time. It kind of goes back
to the concept I talked about earlier
on. You're always investing time or
money, right? The more money you invest,
typically the more time you save. So, if
you're using free or, you know, $20 a
month ChatGPT tool, you're saving money
compared to using, you know, coauthor
cuz it's a little bit more expensive, or
using ghostwriters, but you're probably
going to have to invest a lot more time
in fixing up the content. So, if you
want to do that, you definitely can. If
you want to save a little bit more time,
you can use coauthor or using a
ghostwriter, but this decision is
completely up to you. So, if you're
wondering, "Isn't it unethical to sell
ghostwritten or AI books?" And my honest
answer to this is no. Selling bad books
is bad, right? No matter how it was
created. Because let's be honest here,
just because you wrote the book yourself
without AI, you didn't get any help from
AI, does not automatically make it a
good book. Like, you could write the
book yourself without AI, and it can
absolutely suck. And if you try to sell
that book, and a customer buys it, and
it's super crappy, they're going to be
angry, okay? Because it provides no
value. But, alternatively, if you write
a book that's ghostwritten or you used
AI, but it's actually good, it's packed
full of value, right? A lot of
information, saves people a lot of time,
whatever the value is. And if the
customer buys it, and they get benefit
from it, they'll be happy. They wouldn't
care if it's created by AI or not. Often
times, they're not even going to notice
it's created by AI. So, bottom line, it
doesn't matter how the book is created,
right? As long as the customers are
happy, which means that the book is
high-quality and it has good value, that
is the only thing that matters. All
right, so after you're done writing the
entire book, you want to finish up with
a quick proofreading and editing. So,
whether you get the book back from the
ghostwriter or you write the book
yourself, you want to carefully read
through it to make sure you're happy
with the content. Check for errors,
typos, grammatical issues. You can use
tools like Grammarly for plagiarism
check, as well. And if you use a
ghostwriter, and if you're not happy
with the content, you definitely want to
request for revisions until you're happy
with it. Never accept the book that
you're not happy with. Once you're happy
with the content, the next step is to
format the book. So, you want to format
your book for both ebook and paperback,
so you can sell it in two different
versions. But, if you have an activity
book or journals that doesn't really
apply to ebooks, then you don't need to
make an ebook version. I do have a
step-by-step tutorial on how to format
your book for free using Reedsy. So,
I'll leave a link to this video in the
description. I want you guys to go watch
it and follow along and format your
book. So, book formatting is something
you can definitely do yourself. It's a
bit time-consuming, but it's not too
hard once you learn it. But, if you want
to upgrade the quality of the
formatting, or if you just want to
outsource this entirely, you can find
freelancers that will do this for you.
I'll leave a link to this freelancer.
I've worked with him for literal years
at this point, and he will format your
book for between 50 to $100. Once your
book is created, it's time to create
your book cover. Now, for this one, you
can technically create book covers
yourself, but I highly recommend you pay
a professional. Because your book cover
is one of the most crucial step. It
affects sales so much. People do judge a
book by its cover. And if you have a
crappy book cover that you tried to
design yourself, it's most likely not
going to sell. And again, it's very,
very important. So, at the very least,
outsource it to some of these budget
gigs that I found on Fiverr, which is
only going to cost 10 to 20 bucks.
Preferably, you pay more as you scale
the business, but if you're just getting
started, and if you just want to test
out this business, you can use these
gigs. So, I'll leave a link to this
video. Watch the video. It has the
recommendation of services, and you can
go from there. This is actually one of
the freelancer that I recommend. She
charged $10, and these are the samples.
Like, it's pretty damn good, I would
say. Like, it's a lot better than what
you can probably create yourself using
Canva. All right, so once you have your
book cover ready, now you have all the
book files, and you're ready to upload
to Amazon. So, let's do exactly that.
Step three is uploading the book. So,
first, you want to sign up to Amazon
KDP. Just search Amazon KDP sign up on
Google. It'll take you to a page like
this. Just click sign up, create your
account. Just go through the process,
enter your bank and tax details, so you
can get paid. Now, this is a super
simple process. You shouldn't have any
issues, but if you do, you can watch
this video. I'll leave a link in the
description for a step-by-step tutorial
on this. So, once you log in, it'll look
like this. This is where you go to
create new titles, and you can choose
ebook, paperback, hard cover, or create
a series page. Now, if I walk you
through step-by-step, the video will be
a bit too long, so I'm going to just
link to this video once again on how to
upload a book to Amazon KDP. It's a
complete step-by-step tutorial. Very,
very simple, straightforward. Just
follow this video. Again, the link is in
the description. Once you're done
uploading, within a few days, Amazon
will approve your book, and it'll be
live on Amazon and selling. Now, if you
want to check the sales that you've
made, you just go to the reports tab,
and if you've made any sales, it'll show
up here. All right, now let's talk about
step four, book marketing. So, now that
your book is live and selling on Amazon,
there is a pretty high chance, although
I cannot guarantee, that you will start
making some sales here and there because
Amazon is so big that just by doing zero
marketing, just by being on Amazon, a
lot of times people make some sales.
However, we're talking few sales here
and there, like a couple dollars here, a
couple dollars there, right? It's
definitely not life-changing income. If
you want to scale this so you're
actually making some decent income, then
you do have to do some marketing. So,
you want to get sales and reviews in the
first 30 days of publishing the book to
tell Amazon that your book is in demand.
In any return, Amazon will rank your
book higher in their algorithm, and your
book will be seen to more people.
Because Amazon want to push books that
customers are liking, and also it's
selling because Amazon want to make
money, too, right? So, the more sales
you can get yourself, the more Amazon
will push it, and that means the more
organic free sales you will also get.
So, before sales, you want to get
reviews first because it's a lot easier
to sell books once you have enough
reviews. So, I recommend you get minimum
15 reviews per book before starting
marketing. Reviews act as a social
proof, which makes it much, much easier
to get sales. There are many ways to get
reviews. You can use a Facebook group
method which is essentially just passing
out a free copy of your book in
different Facebook groups associated
with your niche. You can use sites like
BookBounty which is a small monthly
subscription but it saves you a lot of
time or you can use sites like
BookReverb which makes it super simple
and super fast to gather reviews. So I
got this video tutorial on the best ways
to get reviews. I'll just leave a link
in the description but a quick
demonstration of this in terms of how to
do this free. You can use a Facebook
group method which is essentially just
type in whatever keyword associated with
your book, scroll down to groups and you
want to join active groups, right? With
a lot of members and they're making a
lot of posts a day. And once you join,
you want to engage a little bit, get to
know people and then a little bit later
you say, "Hey guys, I just published a
book on this topic. I would love to give
out a free copy of my book in exchange
for your honest feedback. Who's
interested, right?" And you get a lot of
comments, you respond to each one by
sending them a DM. You send them a PDF
copy of your book and then you follow up
around 1 to 2 weeks later saying, "Hey,
how did you enjoy the book?" If they
tell you that they liked it, you can be
like, "Awesome. Do you mind spending a
minute to write a review on Amazon?" And
then you send them the Amazon link. So
that is how you can collect reviews for
free. Obviously, it's very
time-consuming but again, that is a
trade-off if you want to save money. If
you're fine with paying a little bit to
use a service that saves you a lot of
time, the two best ones once again,
BookReverb and BookBounty. I'll leave a
link in the description below. So once
you have enough reviews, it's time to
start getting sales. So Amazon wants to
promote high-quality books that sells.
Nothing tells Amazon that more than
getting reviews and sales first. So you
want to do a little work in the
beginning by getting reviews and sales.
Then Amazon will take over the rest and
that's when the snowball effect kicks
in. So there are many free and low-cost
ways to promote your book and getting
sales but I'll leave a link to this
video in the description. You can go
watch that and you start implementing
it. Essentially, the two most effective
ways are using Amazon Ads which is the
paid method but it's fast or social
media marketing which is free but it
takes longer. Once again, do you want to
invest time or do you want to invest
money? Now Amazon Ads is not as scary as
you think. You're not spending this
crazy amount of money. You can just
start with a couple bucks a day. I do
have a step-by-step beginner tutorial
which is this video. Once again, the
link is below this video. Basically, the
links to all the resources I show you in
this video is in the description below.
Now as for social media marketing, the
best way to get started is with TikTok.
TikTok is the best when it comes to
growing fast. Now you can post a bunch
of different type of videos but the best
one that I recommend is these ones where
you literally just order a copy of your
own book and you showcase the book. This
very very simple video of showing the
book and talking about it got 5.3
million views and generated a lot of
money for this brand. Now you can make
other videos like where you show your
face and you're talking to the camera
but those videos typically get a lot
less views than if you just show the
book and you're behind the camera
talking about it. If you're going to do
social media marketing, you do have to
be consistent though. You cannot just
post a couple videos and see how it
goes. You have to show up every single
day posting at least one video a day for
months. So after you've gone through all
the steps we talked about so far,
congratulations, you're now a published
author. Now if you're happy with where
you're at, you can definitely stop here
but if you want to keep scaling and keep
building your business, you can move on
to step five which is turning your book
into an audiobook. So you cannot create
an audiobook if you have low content or
activity books that doesn't really apply
as an audiobook and that's exactly why I
like high content books, especially
non-fiction books. But audiobooks as an
additional income stream is actually
very very profitable. I have a video on
how I made hundreds of thousand dollars
just from audiobooks so you can make a
lot of money with that. And the process
of turning your book into an audiobook
is very easy. You simply sign up to ACX
which is Amazon's sister company. You
put your book up for audition. You get a
lot of narrators saying, "Hey, I want to
narrate your book." So you listen to
their samples, you pick the one you like
and your book will be narrated. In terms
of the cost, that's also something you
negotiate with the narrator but for a
typical 30,000 word book, it's probably
going to be around $200 one-time
payment. Once again, this is how I made
hundreds of thousand dollars outside of
amazon.com. This is a Facebook group
post that I made when I crossed 100,000
audiobooks sold and this was 2020,
literally like 6 years ago. So I made
way more sales since then obviously and
each sale is about $3.4 in royalties. So
you can do the math there but uh yeah, I
made a lot of money with audiobooks. So
what is next after that? Well, if you
follow these strategies and create a
high-quality book in a in-demand niche,
chances are high that you will start
making sales. Once again, this is a real
business. Nothing is guaranteed. I
cannot guarantee anything but I am
pretty confident that if you follow
these steps and actually take action,
you will start making sales. And by
repeating these steps and publishing
more books, you can make $1,000 per
month or a lot more. Now from here, you
can expand into different advanced
strategies, right? So you can turn this
one book into seven plus more income
streams and you can use these strategies
to scale to 10K per month and much much
more such as audiobooks as we talked
about, publishing your book in other
book stores because Amazon KDP is just a
start. There are other book stores
outside of Amazon where people buy books
from. You can translate your book and so
many more strategies that obviously if I
try to cram it in this video, the video
will be way too long but I cover this
more in-depth in my programs. We have a
lot of students absolutely crushing it
like this student who made $58,000 in a
single month. We have Christine over
here doing over 10K per month or Brock
who made 25K in a single month. another
student who did $40 in her day one, like
literally day one after uploading the
book from her very very first book. And
another student who did over a million
dollars lifetime royalties in about 2.5
years. Once again, guys, I said it many
times and I'll keep saying this. Nothing
is guaranteed. I'm not trying to come
across as this online guru that's trying
to sell you my programs, you know, using
hype strategies, right? I'm not trying
to hype anything up. I genuinely believe
Amazon KDP is the best beginner-friendly
business model to get started but it is
still a real business. And a real
business will require some investments
to grow it, right? It'll require time,
some money to produce these books, maybe
running some ads if you want to scale it
and an investment in terms of your
effort and really showing up every
single day consistently putting in
action. But if you can do that, it's
possible to achieve these results
because we have a lot of students, way
more than what I've showed you that's
absolutely crushing it. It is kind of
crazy right now. So you have everything
you need to know to make $1,000 per
month in this video. But if you want to
take it further, right? And shortcut the
learning curve and shortcut the time to
get to success, then you can join our
coaching program or you can at least
apply to join our coaching program
because we don't accept everyone. It's
the first link in the description. You
can apply for a free 30-minute strategy
call and see if this program is a good
fit for you. Once you join, you'll be
working with a coach one-on-one. You get
access to multiple live workshops and a
very active community of other
publishers. The biggest successes in
publishing typically comes from those
who took our coaching program. All
right. Well, with that being said,
you've made it till the end of the video
so it is time to take action. Once you
follow this video, once you publish a
book, let me know in the comments that
you published a book so that we can
congratulate you. And if you made it all
the way until the end of the video,
you're obviously serious about this
because this video is kind of long. So
let me know that you made it all the way
until the end by commenting I made it to
the end and I'll try to respond to as
many questions and comments as possible.
So if you enjoyed the video, leave a
like, subscribe. Thank you so much for
watching and I'll see you guys in the
next one.